<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs on So</title>
    <link>https://sokinpui.github.io/Blog/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs on So</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 22:33:51 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sokinpui.github.io/Blog/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The productivity of &#39;workflow&#39;</title>
      <link>https://sokinpui.github.io/Blog/post/11-toyeditor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 22:33:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sokinpui.github.io/Blog/post/11-toyeditor/</guid>
      <description>Editor is only useful for editing the configuration file of the editor</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="toy-editor">Toy Editor</h1>
<p>Editor, is for editing text, to get the job done, editing code, notes, configuration file. Some editor have the ultimatly extenability or customizability, like neovim, Emacs or vscode. Often we prepare too much to make our editor prefect, making our editor more than just an editor, convert it into something like git client, terminal, even a social recognition. The idea of hackable editor is great, many of us can get benefits from the scriptability to automation or add handy features. However, extenability come with cost. Emacs, the most extenable editor which come with the powerful extention language, Lisp, with Lisp everything related to text is possible to be implemented. You can, however, the biggest pain is you need to know how to, which involve time and practice to know the api and the language itself.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t be the one who use their editor only for editing their configuration file.</strong></p>
<h1 id="toy-note-system">Toy note system</h1>
<p>Note system is another time sink, because building a note system is much more complex than build a prefect editor. Note system including editor, viewer, a clipper to collect some snippets, the bridge that integrate all your tools, or a all-in-one workspace. Since building note system is much more interesting than writing, review and organize notes, time is easy go to build a superficially clever system that input and output nothing.</p>
<h1 id="the-truth-of-configuration">The truth of configuration</h1>
<p>Yes, one can build their prefect system that will suit their workflow, if their workflow never change, it is not the truth, right? The best note system should always be the next. Your information system will evolve as you behaviour and workflow change.</p>
<p>Implement the change only when you need it, don&rsquo;t even try to make you system prefect, it won&rsquo;t.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim emluation on Emacs and Vscode</title>
      <link>https://sokinpui.github.io/Blog/post/7-tryevil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 11:24:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sokinpui.github.io/Blog/post/7-tryevil/</guid>
      <description>(Edited date: 2023-06-23T11:24:42+08:00)
Emacs Evil mode, a Vi layer on top of Emacs, in my understanding, Evil is a collection of keys remapping that blinds Emacs function to vi style keys. I love elisp, its powerful expression, the robust ecosystem built on top of elisp, tones of API that help writing my own plugins. I thought it is the most apporach Vim emluation I have tried, if Emacs is start as emacs -nw, it will successly pretend Vim TUI!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(Edited date: 2023-06-23T11:24:42+08:00)</p>
<p>Emacs Evil mode, a Vi layer on top of Emacs, in my understanding, Evil is a collection of keys remapping that blinds Emacs function to vi style keys. I love elisp, its powerful expression, the robust ecosystem built on top of elisp, tones of API that help writing my own plugins. I thought it is the most apporach Vim emluation I have tried, if Emacs is start as <code>emacs -nw</code>, it will successly pretend Vim TUI!</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/vscode-neovim/vscode-neovim">Vscode-Neovim</a>, it uses a fully embedded Neovim instance, so Vscode-Neovim can read the <code>init.vim</code> and <code>init.lua</code>. Which is really cool, don&rsquo;t have to google the API before configuraion.</p>
<p>However, I feel the gap when using them. They are great emluation of Vim modal editing, however, other than editing, some important values are still not able to copy, like the integration with shell, and relay on third parity plugin on their ecosystem. Moreoever, I don&rsquo;t feel over advantage to use an emluation than native Vim.</p>
<h1 id="emluation-cant">Emluation can&rsquo;t</h1>
<p><code>Q</code> to enter ex mode in Evil.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<code>q:</code>, <code>q?</code>, <code>q/</code>in Vscode-Neovim(extremely useful!)
<code>sh</code> in both.(sometimes I want to copy the previous command output)
<code>term</code> in Vscode-Neovim to popup an termianl
<code>:help</code> in Evil.</p>
<hr>
<p>(edited at Mon Jun 26 12:49:55 PM CST 2023)</p>
<h1 id="gravity">Gravity</h1>
<p>Merge to new editor is harder than I thought, I have tried Vscode and Emacs, while they are great editor, but just required sometimes to copy the workflow from my old editor to new editor. Even copied all the keyblindings, some minor but unacceptable difference keep consumming my time to google a solution. For example, the Tab completion style difference between Vscode, Emacs and Vim, I like the popup window of Vim, the tab YouCompleteMe style tab cycling, to get the same setup on Emacs and Vscode are terrible.</p>
<p>Also, the greatest gravity fallback to the original editor is no productivity gain from switching. If finally I endup with the same writing and editing experience on other editors, I still reach the same level of speed and productivity, then so what? The core of those editor hasn&rsquo;t changed, editing text, maybe Emacs can extand more than editing text.</p>
<p>After giving a try to those editors, I finally satisify with my current editor. Just be reason when switching tools that have the same functionality in terms of your workflows, especially there is no issue with the current one.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
